Finding Aid for the Alexandra Garrett papers and Records of the Beyond Baroque Foundation, 1965-1991 LSC.1615
UCLA Library Special Collections
Alexandra Garrett papers and Records of the Beyond Baroque Foundation,
1965-1991
UCLA Library Special Collections
Garrett, Alexandra
LSC.1615
8.5 Linear Feet (17 boxes)
Alexandra Garrett was associated with the short-lived literary magazines Coastline and Trace. The first office of Beyond Baroque, a non-profit cultural and educational foundation in the Venice section of Los Angeles, opened in 1968. In the same year, the first issue of its avant-garde magazine, Beyond Baroque, was published, and its art gallery opened. In 1969, the Venice poetry workshops, readings, and music recitals began. In 1972, the Beyond Baroque Foundation was created. The first National Endowment for the Arts grant came in 1974, and by 1977, its library had grown to 10,000 volumes. By 1979, Garrett had become executive vice-president of the Foundation and assistant editor of Beyond Baroque magazine. The collection consists of correspondence, staff bulletins, reports, organizational charts, catalogs, calendars, press releases, board meeting minutes, by-laws, articles and printed materials, scrapbook, clippings and magazines.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Peter L. Garrett, 1992.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9914704903606533
Biography
Alexandra Garrett was brought up in the Eastern U.S., and attended Bennington College in Vermont, editing its literary magazine; moved to Los Angeles; was associated with short-lived literary magazines Coastline and Trace; the first office of Beyond Baroque, a non-profit cultural and educational foundation in the Venice section of Los Angeles, opened in 1968; in the same year, the first issue of its avant-garde magazine, Beyond Baroque, was published, and its art gallery opened; in 1969 the Venice poetry workshops, readings, and music recitals began; in 1972 the Beyond Baroque Foundation was created; the first National Endowment for the Arts grant came in 1974, and by 1977 its library had grown to 10,000 volumes; by 1979 Garrett had become executive vice-president of the Foundation and assistant editor of Beyond Baroque magazine.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, staff bulletins, reports, organizational charts, catalogs, calendars, press releases, board meeting minutes, by-laws, articles and printed materials, scrapbook, clippings and magazines. Includes materials on art and music programs, Olympic poetry festival, book fairs, poetry readings, and film club.
Arts -- California -- Los Angeles -- Societies, etc. -- Archives.; Women periodical editors -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Women poets, American -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Beyond Baroque Foundation; Garrett, Alexandra--Archives.
- Beyond Baroque gallery - art & music announcements. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Beyond Baroque miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Beyond Baroque programs, 1972-1974. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beyond Baroque - Library history & archives. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Readings - past, 1972-1977. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Beyond Baroque chronology. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Beyond Baroque staff bulletins, reports, organizational charts, 1975-1985. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous business, 1981-1982. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Beyond Baroque parties, 1972-1976. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Beyond Baroque fundraising via mail. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Beyond Baroque brochure, 1973-1987. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bayrock Press. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1979-1983. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Manuscripts & correspondence, 1979-1983. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Venice City Hall. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Olympics poetry festival. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Beyond Baroque small press book fair and workshops, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Beyond Baroque rejection slips & manuscript envelopes. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Board of Trustees, Board of Directors by-laws. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Beyond Baroque publicity, news releases. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Board meeting, March 1981. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous poetry readings, 1977-1985. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Readings - miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- New York book fair. (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Friends of books & comics, San Francisco Book Fair. (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- CCLM. (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Zimmerman poems, etc., [?]., 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- UCLA poetry workshop. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Helen Luster's poetry workshop, 1971. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Current poetry. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Poetry workshop. (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence - miscellaneous. (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
- Writers & editors to Alexandra C. Garrett. (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
- Literary magazines, workshops & presses. (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
- Literary magazines, workshops & presses. (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Catalogues. (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
- Film club & film. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Alexandra Garrett letterhead (Beyond Baroque). (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Beyond Baroque, 1974. (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
- Beyond Baroque, 1975. (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
- Beyond Baroque, 1976. (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Beyond Baroque, 1977. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
- Beyond Baroque, 1977. (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Beyond Baroque, 1978. (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
- Beyond Baroque, 1979. (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
- Beyond Baroque, 1980. (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
- Beyond Baroque, 1981. (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Beyond Baroque, 1982. (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
- Beyond Baroque, 1983. (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
- Beyond Baroque, 1984. (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Isherwood reading, - cancelled., February 8, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Beyond Baroque, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
- Beyond Baroque business, 1985. (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Beyond Baroque, 1986. (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
- Beyond Baroque, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Fund raising, 1987. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Beyond Baroque, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Beyond Baroque Vagabond fund raiser - cancelled, 1988. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Beyond Baroque - A night at the movies fundraiser, March 1988. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Beyond Baroque miscellaneous,, including minutes of Board meetings., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- ABA convention guide., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Beyond Baroque, 1989. (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
- Beyond Baroque, - calendar, press releases., 1990 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
- Beyond Baroque Board meeting minutes, 1990. (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
- Beyond Baroque, - calendar, press releases, etc., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 3-5)
- Beyond Baroque, - Board meeting minutes, etc., 1991 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
- Beyond Baroque Foundation by-laws. (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Beyond Baroque building commission. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- VLA. (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Beyond Baroque book fairs - supply checklist. (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Copyright - letters regarding. (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Beyond Baroque calendars. (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Beyond Baroque miscellaneous, ca. 1968-1983. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Beyond Baroque Magazine - forms. (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Beyond Baroque Magazine - procedures & ideas. (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Manuscript forms. (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Beyond Baroque Magazine - forms - original pasteups. (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Articles & printed material about Beyond Baroque. (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
- Articles & printed material about Beyond Baroque. (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
- Magazine: Southern California Women. (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Coastlines - correspondence, 1954-1957. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Coastlines - scrapbook. (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Coastlines - workshops, courses, readings, conferences. (Box 17, Folder 2)
- A.L.M.A. (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Extra Coastlines clippings. (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Coastlines - organization. (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Coastlines - distribution. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Coastlines - events. (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Genesis West. (Box 17, Folder 8)
- California Quarterly - correspondence of interest. (Box 17, Folder 9)